Inventory of the KC PZPR records
Hoover Institution Archives
KC PZPR records
1949-1989
99038
Hoover Institution Archives
17 manuscript boxes, 110 microfilm reels (17.8 linear feet)
Photocopies of minutes, correspondence, reports, and memoranda, relating to political conditions in Poland, and to Polish foreign and domestic policy.
KC PZPR.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1999.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
In part, microfilm.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Archiwum Akt Nowych, Warsaw.
Biographical/Historical Note
Central committee of the Polish communist party.
Scope and Content of Collection
Photocopies of minutes, correspondence, reports, and memoranda, relating to political conditions in Poland, and to Polish foreign and domestic policy.
Supplemental PDF Inventories
KC PZPR (MICROFILM INVENTORY)
Protokoły posiedzeń Biura Politycznego i Sekretariatu KC PZPR 1949-1970
Sekretariat
Sekretariat I Sekretarzy - stosunki międzynarodowe
Communism--Poland.; Poland--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; Poland--Politics and government--1945-1980.
- Box 1, circa 1976
  - Radom U.P., circa 1976 (Text 1: 1-6)
- Box 2, circa 1976
  - Wydarzenia Czerwcowe w Radomiu, circa 1976 (Text 2: 1)
  - Radom U.P. wstępne wersje, circa 1976 (Text 2: 2)
  - Wydarzenia w Radomiu - Czerwiec, circa 1976 (Text 2: 3)
  - Photographs - Radom, circa 1976 (Text 2: 4)
  - Photographs - Radom, circa 1976 (Text 2: 5)
  - Komitet Wojewódzki w Radomiu - Sprawozdanie, 1977 (Text 2: 6)
  - Wypadki Radomskie, circa 1976 (Text 2: 7)
  - Radom, circa 1976 (Text 2: 8)
  - Ursus, circa 1976 (Text 2: 9)
- Box 3, 1981-1989
  - Biuro Polityczne, August 29 - September 17, 1989 (Text 3: 1)
  - Central Committee, Meetings, 1981 (Text 3: 2)
  - Sprawy Międzynarodowe, 1986-1989 (Text 3: 3)
  - Sprawy Wyznaniowe, 1985-1988 (Text 3: 4)
- Box 4, Kolekcja Miedzeszyn, M4 - M6, 1986-1990
  Supplemental PDF Inventories
  Kolekcja Miedzeszyn
  - M4 - Protokoły Sekretariatu KC wraz z decyzjami, 1988 (Text 4: 1)
  - M4a - Finanse PZPR, Nr. 1-39, 1986-1990 (Text 4: 2)
  - M4a - Finanse PZPR, Nr. 40-64, 1986-1990 (Text 4: 3)
  - M5 - Sprawy wewnętrzne PZPR, 1988 (Text 4: 4)
  - M6 - Protokoły i decyzje BP i SKC I-VIII, 1989 (Text 4: 5)
- Box 5, Kolekcja Miedzeszyn M1 - M3, 1986-1988
  - M1 - Sprawy wewnętrzne PZPR, 1986-1987 (Text 5: 1)
  - M2 - Sprawy kadrowe i nomenklaturowe PZPR, 1986-1988 (Text 5: 2)
  - M3 - Protokoły Sekretariatu KC wraz z decyzjami, Nr. 1-12, 1986-1987 (Text 5: 3)
  - M3 - Protokoły Sekretariatu KC wraz z decyzjami, Nr. 13-28, 1986-1987 (Text 5: 4)
- Box 6, Kolekcja Miedzeszyn, M7 - M10, 1987-1998
  - M7 - Protokoły i decyzje BP i SKC IX, 1989-1990 (Text 6: 1)
  - M8 - Sprawy wewnętrzne PZPR, Nr. 1-22, 1989-1990 (Text 6: 2)
  - M8 - Sprawy wewnętrzne PZPR, Nr. 23-43, 1989-1990 (Text 6: 3)
  - M9 - Ann Arbor - relacje (dyskietka i teksty), circa 1998 (Text 6: 4)
  - M10 - Sprawy gospodarcze i referendum, 1987 (Text 6: 5)
- Box 7, Kolekcja Miedzeszyn, M11 - M13, 1986-1990
  - M11 - Sytuacja wewnętrzna, nastroje społeczne, opozycje, Nr. 1-26, 1986-1988 (Text 7: 1)
  - M11 - Sytuacja wewnętrzna, nastroje społeczne, opozycje, Nr. 27-35, 1986-1988 (Text 7: 2)
  - M12 - Geneza “Okrągłego Stołu” (cz. I), Nr. 1-37, 1988 (Text 7: 3)
  - M12 - Geneza “Okrągłego Stołu” (cz. I), Nr. 38-45, 1988 (Text 7: 4)
  - M12a - Geneza “Okrągłego Stołu” (cz. II), 1988 (Text 7: 5)
  - M13 - Wybory czerwcowe (cz. I), 1989 (Text 7: 6)
- Box 8, Kolekcja Miedzeszyn, M14 - M20, 1986-1989
  - M14 - Wybory czerwcowe (cz. II), Nr. 1-23, 1989 (Text 8: 1)
  - M14 - Wybory czerwcowe (cz. II), Nr. 24-31, 1989 (Text 8: 2)
  - M15 - Problematyka międzynarodowa, 1986 (Text 8: 3)
  - M16 - Problematyka międzynarodowa, 1987 (Text 8: 4)
  - M17 - Problematyka międzynarodowa, 1988 (Text 8: 5)
  - M18 - Problematyka międzynarodowa, 1989 (Text 8: 6)
  - M19 - Sprawy wyznaniowe, 1985-1989 (Text 8: 7)
  - M20 - Komitet Obywatelski i KKW NSZZ “Solidarność", circa 1989 (Text 8: 8)
- Box 9, Kolekcja Miedzeszyn, M21 - M26, 1988-1989
  - M21 - Obywatelski Klub Parlamentarny (cz. I), 1989 (Text 9: 1)
  - M22 - Obywatelski Klub Parlamentarny (cz. II), 1989 (Text 9: 2)
  - M23 - Dokumenty czeskie i węgierskie, 1988-1989 (Text 9: 3)
  - M24 - Dokumenty bułgarskie i niemieckie, 1988-1989 (Text 9: 4)
  - M25 - Depesze ambasadora USA w Warszawie, 1989 (Text 9: 5)
  - M26, circa 1990 (Text 9: 6)
- Box 10, Kolekcja Jachranka J1 - J3, 1980-1982
  Kolekcja Jachranka
  - J1 - Protokoły posiedzeń BP 1980-81, Nr. 1-19, 1980-1981 (Text 10: 1)
  - J1 - Protokoły posiedzeń BP 1980-81, Nr. 20-32, 1980-1981 (Text 10: 2)
  - J2 - Protokoły posiedzeń BP 1982, Nr. 1-12 (Text 10: 3)
  - J2 - Protokoły posiedzeń BP 1982, Nr. 13-34 (Text 10: 4)
  - J3 - Stenogramy posiedzeń BP 1982, Nr. 1 (Text 10: 5)
  - J3 - Stenogramy posiedzeń BP 1982, Nr. 2 (Text 10: 6)
- Box 11, Kolekcja “A” (Polska Po Stanie Wojennym 1983-1985), A1 - A4
  Kolekcja "A"
  - A1 - PZPR: sprawy wewnętrzne, Nr. 1-17, 1983-1984 (Text 11: 1)
  - A1 - PZPR: sprawy wewnętrzne, Nr. 18-30, 1983-1984 (Text 11: 2)
  - A2 - PZPR: sprawy kadrowe, 1983-1984 (Text 11: 3)
  - A3 - Sprawa T. Grabskiego, "Rzeczywistości" i ZP "Grunwald" (Text 11: 4)
  - A4 - Stenogram posiedzenia BP KC PZPR w dn. 27 XI 1984 (Text 11: 5)
- Box 12, Kolekcja “A” (Polska Po Stanie Wojennym 1983-1985), A5 - A7, 1982-1985
  - A5 - Stenogram posiedzenia BP KC PZPR w dn. 6 XII 1984 (Text 12: 1)
  - A6 - Polityka wewnętrzna (cz. I), 1982-1985 (Text 12: 2)
  - A7 - Polityka wewnętrzna (cz. II), Nr. 1-11, 1982-1985 (Text 12: 3)
  - A7 - Polityka wewnętrzna (cz. II), Nr. 12-25, 1982-1985 (Text 12: 4)
- Box 13, Kolekcja “A” (Polska Po Stanie Wojennym 1983-1985), A8 - A9
  - A8 - Sprawy wyznaniowe, 1983-1984 (Text 13: 1)
  - A9 - Problematyka międzynarodowa, Nr. 1-15, 1983-1985 (Text 13: 2)
  - A9 - Problematyka międzynarodowa, Nr. 16-24 (Text 13: 3)
- Box 14, Kolekcja Jachranka, J7 - J10, 1980-1982
  - J7 - PZPR: sprawy wewnętrzne przed 13 XII, 1981 (Text 14: 1)
  - J8 - PZPR: sprawy wewnętrzne po 13 XII 1981 (do końca 1982), 1981-1982 (Text 14: 2)
  - J9 - Stan wojenny: przygotowania i realizacja, Nr. 1-20, 1980-1982 (Text 14: 3)
  - J9 - Stan wojenny: przygotowania i realizacja, Nr. 21-32 (Text 14: 4)
  - J10 - “Solidarność” i związki zawodowe (do 13 XII 1981), 1980-1981 (Text 14: 5)
- Box 15, Kolekcja Jachranka, J4 - J6, 1980-1984
  - J4 - Protokoły posiedzeń SKC, 1980-1982 (Text 15: 1)
  - J5 - Finanse PZPR, 1980-1984 (Text 15: 2)
  - J6 - PZPR: kadry, członkowie, nomenklatura, 1981-1982 (Text 15: 3)
- Box 16, Kolekcja Jachranka, J11 - J13, 1980-1982
  - J11 - Sytuacja wewnętrzna, 1980-1982 (Text 16: 1)
  - J12 - Problematyka międzynarodowa, Nr. 1-19, 1980-1982 (Text 16: 2)
  - J12 - Problematyka międzynarodowa, Nr. 20-31, 1980-1982 (Text 16: 3)
  - J13 - Dokumenty Komisji Susłowa (cz. I), 1980-1982 (Text 16: 4)
- Box 17, Kolekcja Jachranka, J14 - J15, 1980-1982
  - J14 - Dokumenty Komisji Susłowa (cz. II), 1982 (Text 17: 1)
  - J15 - Dokumenty czeskie, niemieckie i bułgarskie dot. wydarzeń w Polsce, 1980-1982 (Text 17: 2)
  - Kolekcja M: Materiały pochodzące z zbiorów Hoover Inst.- M1: 25, M8: 17, M10: 5, 9, M11: 16, M15: 13, 15, 18, M16: 3, M17: 1, 2, 9, M18: 1,4, circa 1980 (Text 17: 3)
  - Kolekcja M: Materiały pochodzące z zbiorów Hoover Inst.- M1: 25, M8: 17, M10: 5, 9, M11: 16, M15: 13, 15, 18, M16: 3, M17: 1, 2, 9, M18: 1,4, circa 1980 (Text 17: 4)